https://www.earlyoptionpill.com/more/privacy/

Skip to main content
Welcome
Welcome to www.earlyoptionpill.com! This site is owned by Danco Laboratories, LLC (“we,” “our,” or “us”). This Privacy Policy is designed to tell you about our practices regarding collection, use, and disclosure of information that you may provide via this site and all other company websites or apps that links to this policy (the “Site”). Please be sure to read this entire Privacy Policy before using or submitting information to this Site. This Site is intended for use by residents of the United States.
Your Consent
By using this Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, now and as amended by us. Whenever you browse this Site or submit information via this Site, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
About Children
This Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. We will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information via this Site from visitors in this age group. We encourage parents to talk to their children about their use of the Internet and the information they disclose online.  If you become aware that your child or any child under your care has provided us with information without your consent, please contact us at the contact information listed below.
Information We Collect
Information You Provide
We and our service providers collect any information that you provide when you use the Site, including when you contact us with a question, comment, or request.  The information that you provide can include, but is not limited to, your name, contact information, and transaction-related information.
Information Automatically Collected From You
We and our service providers may automatically collect certain technical information from your computer or mobile device when you use the Site, such as your Internet Protocol address, your browser type, your operating system, the pages you view on the Site, and the pages you view immediately before and after you access the Site.  This information allows us to recognize you and personalize your experience if you return to the Site, and to improve the Site and the services we provide.  We and our service providers may collect this information using a variety of technologies including “cookies,” which are small text files that the Site saves on your computer using your web browser and accesses when you return, or similar technologies.
We may use and combine such automatically collected information to provide better service to Site visitors, customize the site based on your preferences, compile and analyze statistics and trends, and otherwise administer and improve the Site. Such information may be combined with personally identifiable information collected elsewhere on the Site.
Use and Disclosure of Information
Use
Except as otherwise stated, we may use information collected via this Site for a variety of reasons, including: to improve the content of our Site, to customize the Site to your preferences, to communicate information to you, for our marketing and research purposes, and for any other purpose specified. In addition, we may make full use of all information acquired through this Site that is not in personally identifiable form.   We also use information collected via the Site to detect, prevent, and respond to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our terms of use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Site. If you provide personally identifiable information to this Site, we may combine such information with other actively collected information.
Disclosure
We may disclose the information we collect from you through the Site:
to our affiliates and subsidiaries;
to service providers who work on our behalf and who have agreed to use the information solely in furtherance of our operations (such as fulfillment services, technical support, delivery services, and financial institutions);
to business partners who may deliver marketing communications, promotional materials, or advertisements that may be of interest to you;
as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, or to comply with government reporting obligations;
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary (a) to protect our rights, the integrity of the Site, or your safety or the safety of others, or (b) to detect, prevent, or respond to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our terms of use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Site; and
to affiliates, service providers, advisors, and other third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to proceed with the negotiation or completion of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets.
In addition, we may share de-identified reports on user demographics and traffic patterns, as well as de-identified information, with third parties.
The collection, use, and disclosure of information contemplated in this Privacy Policy may involve a transfer of the information to jurisdictions located outside your country of residence that may not have equivalent laws and rules regarding personally identifiable information. By submitting information to this Web site the visitor is authorizing the transfer of such data into the United States.
Security
We take reasonable steps to protect personally identifiable information collected by this Site and to protect such information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. You should keep in mind that no Internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free, so we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information.
Links to Other Websites
This Site may contain links or references to other Web sites to which this Privacy Policy does not apply. We encourage you to read the Privacy Policy of every Web site you visit.  You acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the collection and use of your information by such third parties that are not under our control.
Where is this information processed?
Information collected through the Site will be processed in and subject to the laws of the United States, which may not provide the same level protection for your personal information as your home country, and may be available to the United States government or its agencies under a lawful order made in the United States.  In addition, we may transfer your information outside the United States to our affiliates, business partners, and service providers located in other countries.  By using the Site, you consent to such transfer to, and processing in, the United States and these other countries.
Your Choices
If your contact information changes, if you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us or to have us share your information with third parties for marketing purposes, or if you wish to inquire about the information we have collected about you, please submit a request at the contact information listed below.
If you do not want the Site to collect information through the use of cookies, you can set your web browser to reject cookies from the Site.  Each browser is different, so you should check your browser’s “Help” menu to learn how to change your cookie preferences.  If you reject or block cookies from the Site, however, the Site may not function as intended.
We do not currently respond to web browser “do not track” signals or other mechanisms that provide a method to opt out of the collection of information across the networks of websites and online services in which we participate.  If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Privacy Policy.  Visit the following website, www.allaboutdnt.org
How to Contact Us
If you have any questions, comments, requests, or concerns related to this Privacy Policy or the information practices of this Site, or if you would like to opt out of future communications, please email us at info@earlyoptionpill.com.
Changes to This Privacy Policy
If this Privacy Policy changes, the revised policy will be posted on this Site. Please check back periodically to review these terms. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 12/20/2016.
More
Privacy Information
Site Credits
State Law Resources
Terms of Use
Find a provider
Important Safety Information
What is the most important information I should know about Mifeprex?
What symptoms should I be concerned with?
Although cramping and bleeding are an expected part of ending a pregnancy, rarely, serious and potentially life-threatening bleeding, infections, or other problems can occur following a miscarriage, surgical abortion, medical abortion, or childbirth. Seeking medical attention as soon as possible is needed in these circumstances. Serious infection has resulted in death in a very small number of cases. There is no information that use of Mifeprex and misoprostol caused these deaths. If you have any questions, concerns, or problems, or if you are worried about any side effects or symptoms, you should contact your healthcare provider.
Be sure to contact your healthcare provider promptly if you have any of the following:
Heavy Bleeding. Contact your healthcare provider right away if you bleed enough to soak through two thick full-size sanitary pads per hour for two consecutive hours or if you are concerned about heavy bleeding. In about 1 out of 100 women, bleeding can be so heavy that it requires a surgical procedure (surgical aspiration or D&C).
Abdominal Pain or “Feeling Sick.” If you have abdominal pain or discomfort, or you are “feeling sick,” including weakness, nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea, with or without fever, more than 24 hours after taking misoprostol, you should contact your healthcare provider without delay. These symptoms may be a sign of a serious infection or another problem (including an ectopic pregnancy, a pregnancy outside the womb).
Fever. In the days after treatment, if you have a fever of 100.4°F or higher that lasts for more than 4 hours, you should contact your healthcare provider right away. Fever may be a symptom of a serious infection or another problem.
If you cannot reach your healthcare provider, go to the nearest hospital emergency room. Take the Medication Guide (PDF) with you. When you visit an emergency room or a healthcare provider who did not give you your Mifeprex, you should give them your Medication Guide so that they understand that you are having a medical abortion with Mifeprex.
What to do if you are still pregnant after Mifeprex with misoprostol treatment. If you are still pregnant, your healthcare provider will talk with you about a surgical procedure to end your pregnancy. In many cases, this surgical procedure can be done in the office/clinic. The chance of birth defects if the pregnancy is not ended is unknown.
Talk with your healthcare provider.
Before you take Mifeprex, you should read the Medication Guide (PDF) and you and your healthcare provider should discuss the benefits and risks of your using Mifeprex.
What is Mifeprex?
Mifeprex is used in a regimen with another prescription medicine called misoprostol, to end an early pregnancy. Early pregnancy means it is 70 days (10 weeks) or less since your last menstrual period began. Mifeprex is not approved for ending pregnancies that are further along. Mifeprex blocks a hormone needed for your pregnancy to continue.
When you use Mifeprex on Day 1, you also need to take another medication called misoprostol 24 to 48 hours after you take Mifeprex, to cause the pregnancy to be passed from your uterus.
The pregnancy is likely to be passed from your uterus within 2 to 24 hours after taking Mifeprex and misoprostol.  When the pregnancy is passed from the uterus, you will have bleeding and cramping that will likely be heavier than your usual period. About 2 to 7 out of 100 women taking Mifeprex will need a surgical procedure because the pregnancy did not completely pass from the uterus or to stop bleeding.
Who should not take Mifeprex?
Some women should not take Mifeprex. Do not take Mifeprex if you:
Have a pregnancy that is more than 70 days (10 weeks).
Are using an IUD (intrauterine device or system) (must be taken out before you take Mifeprex).
Have been told by your healthcare provider you have a pregnancy outside the uterus (ectopic pregnancy).
Have problems with your adrenal glands.
Take medicine to thin your blood.
Have a bleeding problem.
Have porphyria.
Take certain steroid medicines.
Are allergic to mifepristone, misoprostol or other prostaglandins.
Mifeprex cannot be used in cases of confirmed or suspected ectopic pregnancy as MIFEPREX is not effective for terminating those pregnancies. If you are using an IUD, it must be taken out before you take Mifeprex.
What are the possible side effects of Mifeprex and misoprostol?
Mifeprex may cause serious side effects.  See “What is the most important information I should know about Mifeprex?” above.
Cramping and Bleeding. Cramping and vaginal bleeding are expected with this treatment. Usually, these symptoms mean that the treatment is working. But sometimes you can get cramping and bleeding and still be pregnant. This is why you must follow-up with your healthcare provider approximately 7 to 14 days after taking Mifeprex. See “How should I take Mifeprex?” in the Medication Guide (PDF) (link to Medication Guide) for more information on your follow-up assessment. If you are not already bleeding after taking Mifeprex, you probably will begin to bleed once you take misoprostol, the medicine you take 24 to 48 hours after Mifeprex. Bleeding or spotting can be expected for an average of 9 to16 days and may last for up to 30 days. Your bleeding may be similar to, or greater than, a normal heavy period. You may see blood clots and tissue. This is an expected part of passing the pregnancy.
The most common side effects of Mifeprex treatment include: nausea, weakness, fever/chills, vomiting, headache, diarrhea and dizziness. Your provider will tell you how to manage any pain or other side effects. These are not all the possible side effects of Mifeprex.
Call your healthcare provider for medical advice about any side effects that bother you or do not go away. You may report side effects to FDA at 1-800-FDA-1088.
General Information about the safe and effective use of Mifeprex.
Medicines are sometimes prescribed for purposes other than those listed in the Medication Guide (PDF). The Medication Guide summarizes the most important information about Mifeprex. If you would like more information, talk with your healthcare provider. If you would like information about Mifeprex that is written for healthcare professionals you may download the Mifeprex Prescribing Information(PDF).
Important Safety Information
What is the most important information I should know about Mifeprex?
What symptoms should I be concerned with?
Although cramping and bleeding are an expected part of ending a pregnancy, rarely, serious and potentially life-threatening bleeding, infections, or other problems can occur following a miscarriage, surgical abortion, medical abortion, or childbirth. Seeking medical attention as soon as possible is needed in these circumstances. Serious infection has resulted in death in a very small number of cases. There is no information that use of Mifeprex and misoprostol caused these deaths. If you have any questions, concerns, or problems, or if you are worried about any side effects or symptoms, you should contact your healthcare provider. Please see additional Important Safety Information and the Medication Guide.
Show more
Be sure to contact your healthcare provider promptly if you have any of the following:
Heavy Bleeding. Contact your healthcare provider right away if you bleed enough to soak through two thick full-size sanitary pads per hour for two consecutive hours or if you are concerned about heavy bleeding. In about 1 out of 100 women, bleeding can be so heavy that it requires a surgical procedure (surgical aspiration or D&C).
Abdominal Pain or “Feeling Sick.” If you have abdominal pain or discomfort, or you are “feeling sick,” including weakness, nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea, with or without fever, more than 24 hours after taking misoprostol, you should contact your healthcare provider without delay. These symptoms may be a sign of a serious infection or another problem (including an ectopic pregnancy, a pregnancy outside the womb).
Fever. In the days after treatment, if you have a fever of 100.4°F or higher that lasts for more than 4 hours, you should contact your healthcare provider right away. Fever may be a symptom of a serious infection or another problem.
If you cannot reach your healthcare provider, go to the nearest hospital emergency room. Take the Medication Guide (PDF)(link to Medication Guide) with you. When you visit an emergency room or a healthcare provider who did not give you your Mifeprex, you should give them your Medication Guide so that they understand that you are having a medical abortion with Mifeprex.
What to do if you are still pregnant after Mifeprex with misoprostol treatment. If you are still pregnant, your healthcare provider will talk with you about a surgical procedure to end your pregnancy. In many cases, this surgical procedure can be done in the office/clinic. The chance of birth defects if the pregnancy is not ended is unknown.
Talk with your healthcare provider.
Before you take Mifeprex, you should read the Medication Guide (PDF) and you and your healthcare provider should discuss the benefits and risks of your using Mifeprex.
What is Mifeprex?
Mifeprex is used in a regimen with another prescription medicine called misoprostol, to end an early pregnancy. Early pregnancy means it is 70 days (10 weeks) or less since your last menstrual period began. Mifeprex is not approved for ending pregnancies that are further along. Mifeprex blocks a hormone needed for your pregnancy to continue.
When you use Mifeprex on Day 1, you also need to take another medication called misoprostol 24 to 48 hours after you take Mifeprex, to cause the pregnancy to be passed from your uterus.
The pregnancy is likely to be passed from your uterus within 2 to 24 hours after taking Mifeprex and misoprostol.  When the pregnancy is passed from the uterus, you will have bleeding and cramping that will likely be heavier than your usual period. About 2 to 7 out of 100 women taking Mifeprex will need a surgical procedure because the pregnancy did not completely pass from the uterus or to stop bleeding.
Who should not take Mifeprex?
Some women should not take Mifeprex. Do not take Mifeprex if you:
Have a pregnancy that is more than 70 days (10 weeks).
Are using an IUD (intrauterine device or system) (must be taken out before you take Mifeprex).
Have been told by your healthcare provider you have a pregnancy outside the uterus (ectopic pregnancy).
Have problems with your adrenal glands.
Take medicine to thin your blood.
Have a bleeding problem.
Have porphyria.
Take certain steroid medicines.
Are allergic to mifepristone, misoprostol or other prostaglandins.
Mifeprex cannot be used in cases of confirmed or suspected ectopic pregnancy as MIFEPREX is not effective for terminating those pregnancies. If you are using an IUD, it must be taken out before you take Mifeprex.
What are the possible side effects of Mifeprex and misoprostol?
Mifeprex may cause serious side effects.  See “What is the most important information I should know about Mifeprex?” above.
Cramping and Bleeding. Cramping and vaginal bleeding are expected with this treatment. Usually, these symptoms mean that the treatment is working. But sometimes you can get cramping and bleeding and still be pregnant. This is why you must follow-up with your healthcare provider approximately 7 to 14 days after taking Mifeprex. See “How should I take Mifeprex?” in the Medication Guide (PDF) (link to Medication Guide) for more information on your follow-up assessment. If you are not already bleeding after taking Mifeprex, you probably will begin to bleed once you take misoprostol, the medicine you take 24 to 48 hours after Mifeprex. Bleeding or spotting can be expected for an average of 9 to16 days and may last for up to 30 days. Your bleeding may be similar to, or greater than, a normal heavy period. You may see blood clots and tissue. This is an expected part of passing the pregnancy.
The most common side effects of Mifeprex treatment include: nausea, weakness, fever/chills, vomiting, headache, diarrhea and dizziness. Your provider will tell you how to manage any pain or other side effects. These are not all the possible side effects of Mifeprex.
Call your healthcare provider for medical advice about any side effects that bother you or do not go away. You may report side effects to FDA at 1-800-FDA-1088.
General Information about the safe and effective use of Mifeprex.
Medicines are sometimes prescribed for purposes other than those listed in the Medication Guide (PDF). The Medication Guide summarizes the most important information about Mifeprex. If you would like more information, talk with your healthcare provider. If you would like information about Mifeprex that is written for healthcare professionals you may download the Mifeprex Prescribing Information (PDF).
